Kodjo KOUDAKPO

Tel: +1 438 221 4971 \$\display \text{Email: kodjo.koudakpo@umontreal.ca/kodjokoudakpo@yahoo.fr}

I am an Economist and Statistician interested in quantitative and qualitative analysis. My area of research involves macroeconomics, fiscal policy, and international economics. I have more than five years of international experience working on questions relating to development, fiscal and public policies, welfare, and poverty reduction. I have also worked on more than 50 national representative household surveys in Sub-Saharan Africa and I speak and write fluently English and French.

PROFESSIONAL AND RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Economist-Statistician Consultant

August 2023 - Now

World Bank Group, Macro, Trade, and Investment Global Practice

Washington D.C., USA

- · Multivariate cluster analysis of livelihood zones in Sahel countries (Niger, Mali, Burkina Faso, Chad)
- · Analytical work on quantitative livelihood zones in the Sahel using LMS survey data.

Research Assistant

May 2023 - July 2023

Observatoire de la Francophonie Economique,

Montreal, Canada

- · Research and technical assistance.
- · Analytical and technical contributions on the economic value of the Francophony in the World.

Economist-Statistician Consultant

Feb 2023 - June 2023

World Bank Group, Poverty and Equity Global Practice

Washington D.C., USA

- · Analytical work on World Bank documents (Poverty assessment, PSIA, Analytical reports, etc).
- · Computation of multidimensional poverty, labor, education indicators, and other socio-demographic indicators in preparation for the Burundi poverty assessment.
- · Technical assistance to the Democratic Republic of Congo (DRC) Crisis Observatory Team on the project Impacts of COVID-19 on vulnerable populations.
- · Building and monitoring the DRC Crisis Observatory welfare and conflict track Tableau Dashboards and high-frequency database.
- · Production of technical and analytical inputs for the socio-economic profile of refugees in Burundi and the Eastern Democratic Republic of Congo.

Economist-Statistician Consultant

July 2021 - June 2022

World Bank Group, Poverty and Equity Global Practice

Washington D.C., USA

- · Data quality assessment and validation of national household representative surveys.
- · Harmonization and analysis of 10 waves of COVID-19 High Phone Surveys (HFPS) in DRC.
- · Technical and analytical inputs to Madagascar HFPS surveys.
- · Analytical and technical contribution in the implementation of a social targeting program in DRC based on HFPS and Enterprise surveys.
- · Monitoring database on poverty, shared prosperity, labor, and education.
- · Technical support for statistical and data development in Africa and data-driven policies.

Economist-Statistician Consultant

July 2020 - June 2021

World Bank Group, Poverty and Equity Global Practice

Washington D.C., USA

- · Technical support for statistical and data development in Burundi.
- · Production of global database monitoring and analysis of the Iterative Beneficiary Monitoring Surveys in Burundi from the Social Safety Net project (Merankabandi).

- · Co-authored "Monitoring health service delivery in Burundi", with Alexandra Jarotschkin, Soazic E. W. Sonne, and Laura A. R. Rivera (2021), World Bank Group, Washington DC.
- · Designing, monitoring, and analysis of phone survey data collection in Burundi on the Social Safety Net projects (Kira and Merankabandi).
- · Training of the Burundi National Statistical Office Staff on poverty and shared prosperity analysis.

Research Consultant

August 2020-November 2020

Research Technical Assistance Center, USAID

Washington, DC, USA

- · Co-authored "Poverty and Malnutrition in Haiti: Findings from Sud and Grand'Anse Departments", with Angelino Viceisza, Kodjo Aflagah, Atabanam Simbou, and Dixita Gupta (2020), Washington, DC.
- · Co-authored "Poverty and Malnutrition in Haiti: Findings from Nord-Est and Centre Departments", with Angelino Viceisza, Kodjo Aflagah, Atabanam Simbou, and Dixita Gupta (2020), Washington, DC.
- · Data quality assessment and validation of national representative DHS surveys in Haiti.
- · Research and technical assistance.

Economist-Statistician Consultant

July 2019 - June 2020

World Bank Group, Poverty and Equity Global Practice

Washington D.C., USA

- · Assessment of water tariff reforms and poverty and social impacts analysis in Niger and Mali for internal communication.
- · Production of a global monitoring database on poverty, shared prosperity, labor, education, and other relevant socio-demographic indicators.
- · Harmonization and analysis of national representative LMS and household surveys.
- · Support for statistical and data development in Africa

Economist-Statistician Consultant

Oct 2018 - June 2019

World Bank Group, Poverty and Equity Global Practice

Washington D.C., USA

- · Research and analytical inputs on the World Bank documents (Poverty assessment, Systematic Country diagnostic, Poverty and Social Impact Analysis, Concepts Notes, etc).
- · Technical support to the Iterative Beneficial Monitoring (IBM) Team on Chad agricultural project.
- · Analytical work on the effect of spatial deflation on urban and rural poverty in more than 40 Sub-Saharan African countries from 2000 to 2019.

Economist (Intern)

July 2017-October 2017

Central Bank of West African States, BCEAO-Headquarter

Dakar, Senegal

- · Analysis of the explanatory factors of the differences between the interest rates of the West African Economic and Monetary Union (WAEMU) member States
- · Developed software on RShiny to monitor indicators on the bank's conditions in the WAEMU

Research Analyst

February 2016-June 2016

Laboratoire de Recherches Économiques et Monétaires, LAREM-UCAD

Dakar, Senegal

- · Analysis of the bank financing and performance of Small and Medium-sized Enterprises (SME) in Cameroon
- · Data processing, cleaning and analysis on the determinants of Cameroon's SMEs performance

Research Assistant

April 2015-June 2015

National School of Statistics and Economic Analysis (ENSAE)

Dakar, Senegal

- · Conception of the sampling technique for a census on production units in the areas of Louga
- · Data processing and cleaning

Research Assistant

July 2014- September 2014

Institut National de la Statistique, des Etudes Economiques et de la Démographie

Lome, Togo

- · Report on Youth Employment Characteristics in Togo
- · Data processing and cleaning
- · Training data collection agents

Research Assistant

April 2014- June 2014

National School of Statistics and Economic Analysis (ENSAE)

Dakar, Senegal

- · Training data collection agents on Survey on household access to primary health care services in Dakar
- · Data collection, processing, and cleaning

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lecturer, University of Montreal

- · Econometrics (Undergraduate): Winter 2022
- · Introduction to Economics (Undergraduate): Fall 2022

Teaching Assistant, University of Montreal

- · Econometrics (Undergraduate): Fall 2020, Winter 2021, Fall 2021, Winter 2023
- · Macroeconomic Theory (Undergraduate): Fall 2021, Fall 2022, Fall 2023
- · Introduction to Macroeconomics (Undergraduate): Summer 2023

EDUCATION

Ph.D. Candidate in Economics,

University of Montreal, Canada

2019 - August 2024

M.Sc. in Statistics and Economics,

National School of Statistics and Economic Analysis (ENSAE), Senegal

2018

B.Sc. in Applied Statistics,

National School of Statistic and Economic Analysis (ENSAE), Senegal

2016

RESEARCH IN PROGRESS

- Fiscal Rules and Fiscal Policy: A Quantitative Analysis
- Geo-economic fragmentation: Implications for the global economy, (with Kodjovi Eklou)
- o Climate change and debt sustainability, (with Fansa Kone and Lucien Chaffa)

POLICY PAPERS

- Monitoring health service delivery in Burundi, with Alexandra Jarotschkin, Soazic E. W. Sonne, and Laura A. R. Rivera (2021), World Bank Group, Washington DC.
- Poverty and Malnutrition in Haiti: Findings from Sud and Grand'Anse Departments, with Angelino Viceisza, Kodjo Aflagah, Atabanam Simbou, and Dixita Gupta (2020), Washington, DC.
- Poverty and Malnutrition in Haiti: Findings from Nord-Est and Centre Departments, with Angelino Viceisza, Kodjo Aflagah, Atabanam Simbou, and Dixita Gupta (2020), Washington, DC.

FELLOWSHIPS, HONORS AND AWARDS

Ph.D. Fellowship, Department of Economics, University of Montreal	2019-Present
Ph.D. Fellowship, CIREQ, University of Montreal	2019-Present
World Bank Group VPU Team awards	2022
Tuition-fee waiver Scholarship, University of Montreal	2019-2021
Excellence Scholarship, United Nations Development Programme	2016-2018
Tuition-fee waiver Scholarship, ENSAE-Senegal	2012-2018
Excellence Scholarship, Odon-Vallet, ENSAE-Senegal	2012-2014

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS AND DISCUSSIONS

Société Canadienne de Science	Economique (SCSE): annual conference	May 2023
18th CIREQ Ph.D. Students' o	conference	May 2023
The Quebec Ph.D. weekly wor	kshop in Economics, Statistics, and Finance	2019-now
Macroeconomics weekly worksl	hop for Ph.D. Students at University of Montreal	2021-now

SKILLS AND LANGUAGES

Statistical Software

Stata, Matlab, R, SPSS, Python, EVIEWS, SPAD, ArcGis, QGis

Other software Word, advanced Excel, VBA Excel, PowerPoint, Latex, CSPRO, EPI-Info, KoBo Data Kits, Tableau Dashboard

Household surveys data LMS & EHCVM (in more than 40 countries in Sub-Saharan Africa), DHS (Haiti, Madagascar), MICS (Madagascar)

Languages

English (Fluent), French (Native), Ewe (Native)

EXTRA-INFORMATION

Leadership roles

- · Member of CIREQ (Centre Interuniversitaire de Recherche en Economie Quantitative), Canada, 2020-present.
- · President of the Association of Togolese Students at ENSAE, Senegal, 2016-2017.
- · General Secretary of the Association of Togolese Students at ENSAE, Senegal, 2015-2016.
- \cdot Treasurer of the Association of Togolese Students at ENSAE, Senegal, 2013-2015.

Qualities

· Teamwork, ability to synthesize, communication and analysis skills, client orientation, passion for international development, data-driven person.

Hobbies

· Traveling, Reading, Game of society, Football, Handball, and volleyball